①+919481722912 ①+919789066602

Graduate in Electronics with experience in Production and Manufacturing of Electronics assembly and Testing with a desire to lead the team by proper utilization of technology, skills, and resources and to be a part of organizational and personal growth.

Designated as **Assistant Manager, Production** at East India Technologies Pvt Ltd, Bangalore

Skills

Production Management
Planning
People Management and General Administration
New Product Life Cycle management.(NPI)
SMT and Through Hole PCB Manufacturing, assembly &Testing

Professional Experience

EAST INDIA TECHNOLOGIES PVT LTD, Bangalore, Karnataka – EMS Assistant Manager-Production, 11/2015 to Present

Manage complete production of Electronic PCB assembly, testing, box building & packing of Printed circuit boards for various Products like Power distribution units, LED Lighting, Networking, and Aerospace etc

Major customers include Schneider Electric, ABB, Lighting Technologies, Unified, Mind tree, EI Labs etc

DIGITAL CIRCUITS PVT LTD, Bangalore, Karnataka – EMS Product & Engineering Manager- 03/2015 to 11/2015 (8 months)

Manage New Products by providing RFQ, Pilot Production and handing over to mass production of PCBs and complete assembly & testing of Energy meters, LED Lighting, Networking products.

Major customers include L&T, Landis&GYR, Invendis, Emerson, Tatapower etc

NOKIA INDIA PVT LTD, Chennai, Tamilnadu – OEM (9 yrs) NPI Lead- 11/2005 to 11/2014

Manage New Product life cycle management, Pilot Production and handing over to mass production of PCBs and complete assembly & testing of Mobile Phones

> APC INDIA PVT LTD, Bangalore, Karnataka – OEM (3.3 yrs) CI Leader - 7/2002 to 11/2005

Supervising production, assembly and testing of Power Distribution Units, UPS, Master Switches for Networking & Communications.

Major customers include Microsoft, IBM, Sun Microsystems etc

BPL INDIA PVT LTD, Bangalore, Karnataka – OEM (9.5 yrs) Production Executive - 2/1993 to 7/2002

Supervising production, assembly and testing of PCBs and Color TV units

Functional Responsibilities

- Achieve Production & Operational goals as per organizational KRA & KPIs
- Recruitment of Production operators & Supervisors
- Monitoring high volume production of SMT&THT boards, manual assembly, testing & boxing of PCB and Units.
- Monitoring OEE Production efficiency, Manufacturing Fail Rate, Scrap & Overall quality of products.
- Coordinating for Shop floor 5s, QMS, EMS & OHS audits and maintaining related documents in Production dept.
- Motivating & rewarding production team members and staffs to participate in gemba kaizens,7 step problem solving, FMEA, Suggestions etc
- Conducting Annual performance evaluation of Production team members & staffs
- Coordinating with support departments in achieving organizational goals.
- Responsible for new products RFQ's & giving inputs to Business Development team
- Perform as functional bridge amongst external vendors as well as internal stakeholders
- Identify improvement areas internally in the manufacturing process as well as perform closely with cross functional teams for implementation solutions
- Implementing systems and procedures for smooth working of Manufacturing and operations
- Leading and mentoring the team for the accomplishment of organizational goals
- Overseeing production related tasks including planning, control and trouble shooting
- Setting up production targets and achieving the targets within time & cost parameters
- Optimizing Man & Machine utilization to achieve preset production goals
- Undertaking time motion study at Production in order to better utilization of 4M's
- Coordinating successfully with internal and external authorities for the smooth working of operations.

Learning's

ISO9001 & 14001 Internal Audit BCMS & OHSAS Audit Lean manufacturing concepts. PMP Training Six Sigma white belt Certification 7 Habits & Leadership training 5s, Kaizen, PWT, SGA Group activities 7OC Toos & FMEA

Educational Qualification

Bachelor of Science in Electronics from Kuvempu University, Karnataka -1992 (Full time)

Personal Details

No of years of experience : 23 years Age : 45 years

Current CTC : Notice Period :

Languages Known (R/W/S) : English, Kannada, Hindi, Tamil

Address

H R VENKATESH "Srinidhi", Budigere Cross, Konadasapura, Old Madras Road, Virgonagar Post, BENGALURU-560049

Date: H R VENKATESH

Place